We're building a platform that enables
AI native software development. And so,
what we've been building so far is
iterations on what that platform could
be and can be tried. We think the right
future for it is a pluggable system.
It's a system that is open, that is
extensible, that is able to allow
builders and tool builders to to build
pieces of it and then allow developers
and developer teams to compose those
into their own unique build workflows.
You're listening to the AI Native Dev
brought to you by Tessle.
Hello and welcome to the AI Native Dev.
This is actually quite a special episode
and it's one in which we're going to be
making quite a significant Tessle
announcement. Guy, why don't you kick us
off with the announcement?
Yeah, indeed. We got a few bucks around
the company. So, we are announcing a
$125 million in funding. This includes a
$25 million seed round that we actually
did back in April that was led by
Boldstart and GV and a $100 million
round that we've just concluded that was
led by Index with participation from
Accel as well as Boldstart and GV again.
So, it's a big news for us. It fuels us.
We'll talk about kind of motivations and
such more, but it sets us up to build
towards that big vision that we have.
So, it's an exciting day.
There we go. And we were so excited we
had to get that announcement out in the
first 30 seconds. Now, let's take a step
back. And as I mentioned, this is a
special podcast. I'm going to be the
host for this podcast and Guy,
unusually, you're not going to be the
host for this podcast. You're going to
be one of the people that I'll be
interviewing. Let's do some intros
for me. My name's Sam Maple. I'm the one
of the hosts usually of the AI Native
Dev podcast. I work for yourself Tessel
and I run DevRel at Tessel. Guy Po,
would you give us a brief introduction
for those who don't know you?
I am the founder and CEO of Tessel.
Before that, I founded Snyk, which I
built into a multi-billion dollar
company with an amazing group of people
around me in the developer security
space and I am the co-host here of
yourself Simon on it and have a pretty
kind of rich background before that
building developer tools in the devops
space.
Wonderful. And we also have Ben
Galbraith.
Delighted to be here. I joined Tessel, I
guess it's been about two months to lead
product and delighted to be here. As
part of joining Tessel, I've moved to
London from the Bay Area, California.
Huge move for us. I've got a bunch of
kids that have come with me and my wife
as well. And prior to joining Tessel, I
was at Google for a number of years with
product and design leadership roles on
Firebase and Chrome and identity and
before that where where we met was when
I was at Walmart Labs running product
design and the front engineering for
Walmart's global e-commerce stuff and
before that did a bunch of stuff,
Mozilla and Ajaxian talking about the
dynamic web back in the day and a bunch
of other roles and really delighted to
be here on the Tessel team.
Yeah, and it's fun and Ben and I have
been talking about doing something
together for I guess pretty much since
those kind of Walmart Labs days.
15 years, yeah.
It's really fun to get the opportunity
to all I required was to have him move
his family over here to London.
To do over here but then it's a big
adventure.
Yeah, we're we're super excited.
Wonderful. In the celebratory move, why
don't
Probably.
pass across some bubbles and
And so that people on the podcast as
well as on the video can join us. Let's
let's cheers in front of the microphone.
So cheers. 125 million to Tessel. So
cheers to all.
Mhm.
So AI yes, AI native development. We
know before we talk about the
announcement of the money, the green in
too much depth, let's talk a little bit
about the space.
Now we know because of this is the AI
native dev podcast, we know the space
that Tesla is in, which is AI native
development. Let's first of all, and I
know we talked about this guy in the
first episode, but let's go a little bit
deeper now and just talk about see how
that's changed.
First of all, let's start with the pain
points. So, when we think about AI
native development as potentially a
solution or a new paradigm in which we
see development going forward, what are
the shortcomings of how software is
developed today?
So, our premise is that today software
development is code-centric. And the
code couples within it both what the
system does and how it does it. And it's
written into the very same lines, right?
Like as a developer or an LLM, you're
reading the code and you're trying to
parse out from the implementation both
what the application does and how it
does it. Maybe you're helped by some
comments. And this is just the reality
of software development. The code
becomes the source of truth and over
time it gets more and more hairy to
maybe parse it out. It gets bigger, the
logic becomes more refined and
optimized. An edge case adds an if, the
comments get out of whack because
there's no immediate value to
maintaining them or the documentation.
And so, the code continues to to grow
coupling this what and how and they
become very hard to remove and separate.
And that really creates a fragility
challenge in the software that gets
built up. Every time you modify the how,
which is necessary every time you
maintain the software, it lives in a
dynamic environment. And so, there's a
dependency that changes open source
a component or framework or an operating
system or a service that you use. And
so, all of these things change, you have
to change the system. Of course, you
evolve the the the system, you add a
feature, it might break another feature.
And every time you do that, it's very
hard to know that you haven't modified
what the application does.
Once again, like if you're amazing at it
and for a while you would build tests.
And even the tests, they combine both
testing what the system does and how it
does it.
And so, it really grows over time and
it's just been our reality. We try to
tackle it with breaking the system out
into smaller components and things like
that. Uh but fundamentally, it's the
core challenge uh that exists in
software development. Uh and we think
there's an opportunity, which we can
talk about, to separate those with the
world of AI uh for a variety of reasons,
and we think that would help make
software easier to create, but also
easier to maintain over time and make it
less fragile and easier to improve and
optimize.
I really like the articulation of the
sort of what and how, and it feels as an
industry we've been trying to do this
for a while. I think about, I don't know
how many people looked at what Charles
Simonyi was doing with this thing called
Intentional Software 20 years ago, but
he also had this observation that you've
got a description of the system in
documentation and comments, and then
you've got code, which is a parallel
rearticulation, and he tried to make the
comments be the canon of the behavior
and to derive the system, and I just
don't think they had the tools that were
necessary, and that's what's so exciting
about the world we live in now with LLMs
having this ability to fill in the gaps.
And I think that's tantalizing. We've
all had this experience with things like
Claude and and ChatGPT. It's seen what
happens when you have a brief
articulation, and then you see the LLM
filling all these gaps, but that sort of
leaves a lot of questions about, okay,
so I've generated a lot of stuff, but
how do I maintain it? And doing that in
a dialogue with sort of a chat agent is
a way to do it, but I think we've all
found that it's not a very satisfying
way to do it. And so, one of the ways I
think about what we're doing at Tessell
is how can we take what the LLMs have
proven to be really good at and
structure code in a way where you can
have an ongoing maintenance
relationship. And then one of the other
big challenges is how do you validate in
a meaningful way that the LLM got it
right? Because randomness is baked into
the system. Like all these models have
this notion of temperature, which is
explicitly about don't do what you think
you should do, do something random.
yeah.
That's right. And so, you really have to
have some sort of a validation story
coupled with this gap-filling ability
that LLMs bring to the table to bring
spec-driven development to life.
And And that's interesting that it's
essentially the LLMs, the AI, that's
unlocked this. Obviously, there are a
ton of tools around
as well today.
A few. One every day. What is it about
AI assistants that doesn't plug this
hole, doesn't satisfy the shortcoming in
where we are talking about development
today?
Yeah, I think there's at least two ways
to think about it. One is the power
we're seeing for these tools to augment
the code that you write today. And
that's a really powerful use case
because it's really clear that these
models are fantastic at generating
snippets of code. And you have this
opportunity to roll the snippet multiple
times, too. And And this is a really
natural expression of what these things
are good at. But if you take a step back
and you ask yourself, how do you create
an entire system in this way?
It's really a different challenge. And
so, that's one thing that I think that
separates what we're doing from the sea
of tools that are out there. And
occasionally, I see a few companies that
are tackling this challenge, but by and
large, it still seems to be a pretty
wide-open space to figure out how you
can take these LLMs
and create a way of programming that
capitalizes on what they're good at and
recognizes what they're not good at and
create truly scalable systems on top of
that. And I'm preaching to the choir
here, but it's such a different way of
thinking about software that it
motivates a whole new category. And
that's what we're calling it Tessel AI
native software development. To me,
that's what that term is really trying
to express. It's that it's a new way of
developing. How with cloud, when you
really think about cloud and what cloud
makes possible, you don't want to take a
VM and shove it into the into sort of
some cloud host. You want to really
think differently about how you design a
system to take advantage of cloud. And
that's really the type of journey that I
think we're going to have to be on to
really create entire software systems in
this way. That's how I think about it.
Yeah. And I think that's a really good
description around almost like
systematizing how do you capture your
intent, which often times users they
express in words, the LLM fills in the
gaps, and and it's useful. But how do
you then continue from there? What
remains? Which to me is indeed the
second aspect, which is eventually today
a lot of these tools are different UX
for generating code. They go through a
more or less elaborate process of
creating something, and then eventually
they produce code, and the code is the
long-lived asset. The code is the thing
that lives from version to version.
Actually, most of these applications
don't really have a life that is that is
longer term, right? So, they build those
out, and and maybe you export that, and
you continue to work with it in Python
but really all it does is it it modifies
the code. So, very powerful new user
experience for the code, but the code is
the asset that continues. So, it
continues to conflate this how and the
what. And the the intent when we talk
about spec-centric is that spec will
capture the intent. What is it that the
user has wanted, including verification
that we have a lot to do on defining
them to say, "What do you want, and how
do I verify that what was produced
satisfies those needs?" And this is the
the thing, the artifact that we continue
nurturing over time. We continue
building out over time. And once you
have this great kind of niche like
central entity that says what you want
and how to verify it's correct, now you
can really tap into that creativity of
the LLM, and you can imagine multiple
stages of non-deterministic creative
LLM-powered or other optimizations and
improvements that adapt that
implementation, that improve that
implementation. So, I think that's
really exciting, and that is that
spec-centricity. As long as you don't
create the new asset, as long as all you
do is you generate the code, you always
have to decipher back what was the sort
of the implementation intent, and what
was the intent in it. I think I want to
highlight also one more thing. It It's
pretty obvious that the one unlock here
is that machines can write code. Fine.
LLMs can implement this, and we're
capturing it, but also we're we're
taking for granted maybe a little bit is
the is this comment you made quickly,
which is uh filling the gaps. Today, you
can provide the the machine, the system,
an incomplete spec, and it will fill in
the gaps. If you you can say, "Create a
Tic-Tac-Toe game." and not say what are
the rules of Tic-Tac-Toe, because the
LLM knows.
Yeah.
That that's amazing, and it makes specs
viable. If you compare them to the
formal specs of old that are just so
painful to use,
right.
it makes them viable, but it also
represents trouble.
Yeah.
It also represents a problem. It's like,
"How do I know which decisions uh it
made?" which is another reason for
needing the new development paradigm,
because we have to figure out how do you
interact with the LLM's decisions? How
do you figure out what it did? How do
you define degrees of freedom between
the spec and the implementation? And all
of those
they require a craft. They require some
formation, which is what we're trying to
build.
Yeah, it's super exciting, because it
feels like the industry's wanted to go
here for so long. I think about
test-driven development, and I feel like
test-driven development wanted to
motivate the style of development, but
when you, the human, are writing the
tests and the implementation, it's just
too much labor. It's too much toil, and
there are a few shops that have managed
to make it happen, but most people just
don't get there. And now we have another
opportunity to think in this way. I
don't think specs will feel like a list
of tests than TDD, but I think the craft
will feel similar to people who develop
software that way, and should also say I
started as an engineer, but for most of
the past, I'd say, gosh, 12, 13 years,
I've been more on the product side than
I've been on the engineering side.
And to me, that's what makes spec-driven
development really resonate, cuz I'm a
technical person, but I don't really
care about what the current sort of
fashion is for Swift or for TypeScript,
and and I don't want to learn new best
practices, but I I am very comfortable
thinking very technically about what a
system should do. And if there's some
new hot way to enumerate a data
structure, if there's some new pattern
for doing asynchronous callbacks, I
don't really want to learn that, but I
am very happy to spec out in
collaboration with the LLM behavior
that's a little bit higher level than
that and to get a lot of leverage from
that. And we'll figure out the right
level for where the specs should live,
and that's something that I think I'm
really excited about with our community
approach to engage the community in
figuring that out together. We have
concrete ideas with our current
implementation, but we'll see if they're
at the right level of abstraction, but
I'm really excited about this general
level of altitude of thinking
technically about what the system should
do without having to get into the actual
weeds of writing the implementation of
everything myself and being productive
in in that way.
Yeah, and that's great that you're just
starting to lean into a little bit of
talk about the implementation and how
we're
of the code, but implementation of a of
a platform.
Of Tessell. And every single time that
we talk about AI native development
publicly, people go, "This sounds really
interesting. It sounds very much like a
future that's very possible. But what
does Tessell do?" And I think, you know
what? We've got a bit of money now. I
think it's time to get a little bit more
concrete, right?
So, let's talk a little bit about First
of all, the seed, so the 125 million has
been raised so far. That's in two
buckets. That's a 25 million seed that
was led by Boldstart and GV, and then
100 million for a series A. So, let's
first talk about the seed. When did that
happen, Guyper?
It happened back in April in practice
over March with the two investors
building it out. It would have taken us
a moment to get all the people working
in place. And that helped us get off the
ground. It helped get sort of two great
partners for the journey and Ed Sim at
Boldstart and Tom Hume at GV. I I'm I'm
happy to be in a position in which I
have more freedom to operate, and part
of it is getting amazing people to to
join the journey and pursue a big
mission on it. And it helped on the
fundraising side. It was easier than
before, but I think it's very important
when you build a business to be
accountable. So, it needs to explain to
people. I'm a bit of a control freak. I
don't like giving up control, but I do
think accountability is healthy, needing
to explain your actions both to the
people around you and to investors. So,
that was good and that was a an opening
shot to say, "Hey, we're building
something real here. It's not some sort
of whim that guy is talking about over
here, but a true mission." And that
really is demonstrated by getting a
great group of people around it, and
getting a decent round of funding from
top-tier investors.
Mhm. I can If I can add a different
perspective, too, just as someone who
talked to Guy a lot during this period
of time, and if come in relatively late
in the journey so far, I'm just really
excited about what Guy was able to do
with the fundraising, because the
initial round demonstrated that serious
people had confidence in the vision that
Guy had.
But, when Guy started to talk through
the potential of doing a larger round,
it was really a powerful validation of
the concept and vision that Guy had
incepted with the team. And not to
repeat your words, and also the team
that we've been able to recruit here at
Tessell. We're now about 20 people. It
really gave us what we needed to be able
to go the distance, because this is a
bold new vision. It's going to be a long
journey to figure this out, and we're
helping to incept a whole new category.
And it was really important, I felt,
just again, as as a newbie outsider, to
see that we had the capital to be able
to sustain this journey, and that we
weren't going to be under pressure to
try to figure this out, and are we going
to have to make compromises and go in
weird paths.
We have enough capital to really see
this through, which is just a really
exciting place to be. And that's my
perspective as well.
I agree.
And Guy, this is interesting, actually,
cuz
whenever, like with startups, timing
matters. Guy, obviously, with 125
million now, that puts a lot of cards in
your hand. What does that mean from a
timing aspect?
Yeah, so I think there are a bunch of
reasons to indeed add the round. Ben
just mentioned a few, which is to give
us stability to go the distance, and
give everybody involved, ourselves to
build the right thing, the community to
say, "Hey, we can invest in this. Some
of these things will materialize very
quickly. Some will take a while." Our
customers, our would-be customers to
know that this is solid foundation that
they can build upon. And so all of those
were important to uh go further. They
didn't have to happen right now. Uh we
haven't quite consumed much of the $25
million that were originally invested,
but I think the opportunity came to just
get a a really great investor in Index
and Carlos and then have Excel
participate. Again, fundamentally, I
guess having been in this world for a
while now both as the founder of Sneak
and building that out, but also with the
many angel investments that I've made,
getting the right investors on board,
it's not a trajectory-changing
path for the company, but if you get the
partners the right partners to be with
you for the journey, them as individuals
can be very valuable. They offer a
different lens on the world because they
look at the macro. They start by looking
at the whole market and the whole path.
You're building the company and then you
have people in the team that look at the
very bits and bytes and the low levels
and that completeness of perspective is
very important. Carlos was the CTO at
GoCardless before this. In general, I've
known him for over a decade, I think
now. And so having that that right lens
is very valuable. It's also useful, and
I see this now in Sneak, to have people
that have been along for the journey
because they build with you the
appreciation of what's important to
maintain. And because we're we're
planning here on a long-
lived company, right? On a company that
would eventually go public and would be
a sustainable company in the industry,
it's important for those kind of
significant shareholders and original
investors to have that conviction around
where it's going and not just be excited
by the traction or or the path. We're
early in it, and I think this investment
on the investor side, of course, I'm
putting words in their mouth, but it
really comes in because they are excited
by the team, they're excited by the
vision, and they're excited to build it
together. They themselves believe in the
thesis in the change that will happen,
and they want to be part of it. So it's
great.
I also want to clarify one thing.
Sometimes when you have these large
raises with an AI company, it's clearly
destined to fuel the development of
something like a new foundational model
or some other complex deep model
development. And wanted to clarify
that's not our vision. We think we can
get where we need to go on top of the
existing foundational models and other
models that are emerging from the
ecosystem. So, don't think about this
raise as being motivated by a race to
burn in order to out-innovate some of
the other foundational model vendors.
This is really about having the
resources to build the team that we need
to create what we're trying to create
with $25
you were able to afford myself. And then
with the change
I needed the $100 million
With the change, you were able to buy
hire another 19 20
No no no publicly obviously Tessell's
done a fair amount already. This podcast
we've launched a virtual conference
which is happening on the 21st of
November all around AI native
development and some of the tools and
practical advice about how organizations
can get started using AI powered tooling
today. We've launched a community last
week which is the AI native dev
community. Go on to Discord you can talk
with like-minded people and talk a
little bit about how we're getting on
with Tessell as well but it's a vendor
neutral community there. When we think
about what's actually happening under
the covers though, things that we
haven't announced. Is there anything
more we can talk about the platform,
what we're actually building, what we've
got today?
Look, at Tessell we're building a
platform that enables AI native software
development. And so, what we've been
building so far is iterations on what
that platform could be and and can be
tried. We've been working with sort of
friendly users to to give us feedback to
see which parts are terrible and which
parts are are compelling. Our own team
is using it and we do these hackathons
of trying to create tiles which are our
unit of software and
seeing what we like about it and what we
don't. We've been iterating we're on
second major generation of the platform
even though it hasn't seen in light of
day. We are iterating on it. Uh
substantially, and we're building it out
towards an early 2025 beta to start
putting people into it. There's an
interesting mix here in which on one
hand we firmly believe in shipping it
and in being out there and in allowing
users to tell your product is terrible
and tell you hopefully say why so you
can fix it and you can improve it. And
since we're trying to build something
big, we have no illusion of getting it
right on the first take. Uh at the same
time, we want to be respectful of
people's time. We don't want to just
have everybody face problems that we can
already identify and address. We want to
be able to demonstrate enough of the
sort of enticing future of AI native
development and give users an
opportunity to engage with them. And so
we're working between those. It's
important for me to just further
emphasize is that there's a risky trend
that happens with every new technology
trend, but specifically in the world of
AI, to favor walled gardens, to favor
small closed ecosystems that are very
opinionated. It's easier to to grok,
absorb, a new technology that's
something disruptive as AI within that
more confined context. And a lot of the
companies in the space right now are are
naturally leaning towards that. Hey, I
will do the end-to-end thing. And we
actually discussed this in the podcast
several times. And and Matt from Netlify
just mentioned this but context of the
web. And we talk about is it one product
that understands the code base and
therefore offers you everything around
it or is it composable? We believe in an
open ecosystem. We think eventually tech
moves, shifts, new ideas, new
technologies come along, different
innovators build different pieces of it.
And so what we're building while we we
aim to build a sustainable end-to-end
flow that doesn't require something
else. You'd be able to use it and and
produce powerful things on it
on its own. We we think the right future
for it is a pluggable system. It's a
system that is open, that is extensible,
that is able to allow tool builders to
to build pieces of it in allow
developers and developer teams to
compose those into their own unique
build workflows. And so we think a lot
about all these moving parts and try to
bring them in to this initially more
contained community that we'll start at
the early next year that again will call
us on
all the sort of silliness that we might
have in the platform and and will allow
us to improve the product and we will
grow that group as we improve the
platform.
From a product perspective, this is one
of the more interesting decision points
is at what point do we bring the system
out to engage the community because we
have these expansive visions across so
many dimensions about what we want to
do. Like we have ambitions for what
spectrum of development means and we
have milestones along the way that sort
of take us there and there's a
temptation to release it at the first
milestone. But do we wait or do we
refine it? Do we prove it out or do we
just let the community give us feedback?
And we think about that with our
generator. We think about that with the
way that we generate documentation with
the system. We think about that in terms
of like the types of systems that we
facilitate you building. There's
decomposition a big part of the system.
This notion of if you have a really
complex system that you want to build,
how do we help you factor that into
simpler parts that can be effective? And
how much do we want to invest in the
decomposition engine? And what's anyway?
Just this balance of figuring out the
right moment to surface it for the
community is a challenge and it's a fun
one.
And over the last few months obviously
with various product advancements from
Tesla engineers,
are there anything you want to call out
as specific learnings in terms of
obviously we've been sharing with
certain friendlies who are giving us
feedback on the product. Are there
certain things that our listeners can
take away with really interesting
takeaways?
One thing that's just lately on my mind
from the latest testing session and
feedback session is the relationship of
the information generated because
there's a sort of asymmetry from the
input you have in the system. Like I
want a system that does X for example. I
want a system that's a silly example is
I I want a utility that helps me convert
between color spaces and you have
something that's really simple and then
you put that in the system and it can
generate a ton of information from that.
We have the ability in the system to do
like a big one-shot generation if we
really wanted to that sort of decom-
decomposes that into different pieces
and create specs of the different pieces
and a lot of code, but it can be
overwhelming for people to process. If
you go from like a prompt that's just
drop of like dozens of sort of pieces
and we're really thinking through what
is the right creation journey to go and
do we really want to bring you in an
attended fashion along multiple steps in
that journey? And I think we're finding
that for some users the answer is yes.
They very much want to go along the way.
They want an opportunity to look at
decisions that the system has has made
the sort of gap filling we talked about
earlier
and understand it along the way and
maybe influence it. Whereas other people
just feel like give me your best shot
and I'll take a look at it and I'll
decide if I like what you generated.
That's one of the design challenges that
we're puzzling through at the moment.
It's also interesting that eventually we
think all of those workflows are
legitimate. There isn't one way you
develop software. Sometimes you build
something basic and then you decorate
and you expand it. Sometimes you design
something quite elaborate at the
beginning and you build it. Neither of
those is correct or incorrect. They're
just, you know, what whatever fits that
person in the current setting. And so
eventually software development should
have flexible workflows. You should be
able to choose those. But at the moment
we're trying to shrink it to something
that is shippable that people can start.
And related to that is this debate of
customizability. We want to demonstrate
AI native development and one path of
temptation is we're going to pick a
workflow that is the workflow of
generating that is AI native that is
specs and trick, but that accommodates
only one option of those things versus a
second path that is actually like
injecting in a bunch of these places
extensibility and tinkering and
modification which we want to enable
because we think that is the right path
and and also would be relevant to our
users. But there's a certain amount of
the more options you give the less
streamlined the experience. So I think
all of that is really interesting. To me
probably the biggest learnings are in
the world of what the LLMs do and do not
do well today. And this challenge of
capturing generation in a delivery plan,
right? And how do you bring it forward?
How do you advance it? I think it's
interesting. The LLMs are very good at
certain generations and then not so much
at others. One thing that I was
dismissing at the beginning is how much
they're willing to cheat. You know, if
you give them as a part of that spec,
you give them the tests. Initially the
team was quite concerned about them
cheating and writing if statements. They
said, "Oh, you told me that the test is
if I get three I return seven." Uh so,
it'll just write code that says, "If I
give you three I return seven." So, it's
like, "Nah, that's not like the LLMs are
not designed to cheat. They're designed
to give you correct answer." And then
they would also do it. Lo and behold,
they cheat
quite well. There's all these like human
traits of how the LLMs behave. And it's
interesting cuz sometimes the the way to
address those are human emphasis. Either
you like emphasize in the prompt to say
do not do that, or you supervise, you
introduce a critic that says, "Did they
cheat? Did they cheat?" They say same as
pretend code, right? You tell it
generate a QR code generator. It says,
"Here's the placeholder for the QR code
generator." No, I told you to generate
this, not to And so, I think dealing
with these eccentricities of the LLM is
to me the the primary insight. For us
like in terms of sharing, I think
there's just a lot and some of those I
think are probably learned by every AI
dev tool out there. I think we try to
focus more on
what is the software development process
here and build these things because we
think some of these problems we will
solve and some of them we will give the
sort of the workflow, the the system,
and we actually want to tap into the
kind of creativity and and brilliance of
others to to say here's how I solve it
or even this is how I solve it for my
specific scenario.
That's right.
Let's jump back to the hundred million
series A guy. What do you think about
these AI startups and companies that are
raising stupid amounts of money and on
ridiculous valuations? What would you
say?
We could have raised at a higher
valuation, but we chose to be robust
here and and choose a modest valuation.
I'm just joking. We raised at a pretty
good number. I think there's a whole
bunch of reasons why this happens and I
think some are better than others. I
think there are definitely companies
that are just blinded by the sort of the
sheer numbers and investors.
Investors have very complicated
incentives. You can go from the most
cynical route, which is some investors
are playing the fees game. Like
investors get paid both on carry of
return or a portion of the returns that
they bring their investors and on fees.
So if you're like most cynical, you can
talk about them just deploying fast
amounts of money, they're still going to
make a lot of money. You can talk about
just like learnings, they have to be in
the game, they have to try them out and
even if there's a few failed
investments, they have to do it. But
also there's just firm belief that some
of them, you don't know which ones, but
some of them will like look at OpenAI,
you know, become incredible businesses.
OpenAI's valuation is eye-popping, but
their business is pretty ridiculous in
how quickly it grew to like billions in
revenue.
And so
I think there's definitely an element of
true belief. I do think that within
these fund raises, there's you can
loosely split them into these two camps
that Ben mentioned. One is big raises
that are needed because you need big
money to buy GPUs and train your system
on it. And those are harder for me to
grasp. I think again, people have all
sorts of thoughts about them, but they
very industrial to me in nature. You
have to depreciate to these models very
quickly. So like you're building a
factory to train the model and then
you're burning it down. There's power
that gets lost.
I have to say as someone who's new to
the UK, it reminds me of F1 in a sense,
right? Like before the budget cap,
right? Like you can field a team on a
shoestring budget, but you're probably
going to lose to Ferrari, Mercedes and
maybe McLaren and all that.
They're really well-funded because I
think of the the big vendors in the
space, the big players that we all know,
OpenAI, Google, Anthropic. It's hard to
imagine that any startup, even if you
have a fantastic raise, can go the
distance.
If you're playing this game, you have to
have that money. So, the startups make
sense to me, and the investors is just a
question. And then you have the other
set, which I believe we are part of,
which is the reason they're raising the
large rounds is because they're taking
on a big mission. And we are seeking to
go the distance and do something big.
Yeah, those are just opportunities.
Mhm.
There's sort of two reasons not to raise
money. One is optionality. Basically,
every time you raise, you're doubling
down on the company because you've just
raised the valuation for any potential
exit or acquisition. And I think we're
quite committed. I can definitely say
for myself, and I think the team,
everybody came in with that conviction,
which is we're trying to build something
big. And so, for us, it was less of a
factor. And two is if you spend the
money ahead of actually being ready to
spend the money. So, you you use it
unwisely.
Mhm.
And I think over here we were relying on
our discipline, with the experience in
the team and myself, to be smart about
how we how we spend the money, and to be
ready to hit the gas when we are ready,
but not to create fake product market
fit sensation by spending money. And
that's why you have to sell that
Ferrari.
Is that why this Is that why this is
just apple juice and sparkling water?
Exactly.
So, let's talk about the future then.
And let's let's finish off with that.
Can I push you on a on a month, day, and
time for the product release?
15th at 4:00 p.m.
Okay.
We haven't decided on the launch date.
We think about it more in terms of
making sure that the product is ready
for this community that we want to give
it to, so that it really doesn't waste
their time.
Mhm.
We're innovating on
uh what it means to do AI native
development, and we want to find the
right starting point where you see the
vision we have, and you can realize
aspects of that vision in the system,
and we have meaningful extension points
where people can put their labor into it
and move things forward. What we're not
trying to do is have a Tessel
proprietary platform and invite
volunteers to enrich Tessel. We're
really trying to create a community that
is expansively defining this category
together and we're providing some tools,
but we want people to really feel like
the skills that you're creating by using
this tool are general skills that will
apply to this new category that we're
that we're helping to create with the AI
native development.
Mhm.
So we we are planning to have something
ready in early 2025. That's the target.
We're not more specific than that, but
we really do want to bring it out to
develop it in the open with the
community and not be in a lab doing an
R&D project for the next 2 years.
Yeah, yeah. So something definitely
within the first 12 months.
I thought you said December 15th, no?
Did you hear December?
This is our general rubber conversation.
We talk about I think we have all have
strong conviction to say to ship it to
bring it out there and indeed it is
balanced with that sort of desire for
breadth. Good opportunity to maybe call
out for the listeners is we have now
opened our waitlist and so you can now
go to Tessel.io and sign up for the
waitlist. You can tell us a little bit
more about yourself. That would help us
pull you in sooner because we want a
variety of users within our early
community and we're very keen to open
that up and so nobody is more impatient
than us in bringing it out there. So I'd
encourage the listeners here to sign up
and
we will pull you in as soon as we can
and in the meantime we'll keep you
posted about development and would love
for you to engage in our community in
the upcoming conference.
Yeah, absolutely. The waitlist is great
for the product and then of course if
you're just dying to carry on talking
about this, of course we have the
podcast so feel free to subscribe to
that. We obviously have the the Discord
community which you can connect to from
our website AI Native Dev Con which is
happening in a couple of days actually.
Let's talk more on the community. Ben,
Guy, thank you very much for joining.
Simon.
And congratulations to all of us and
everyone at Tessel for this amazing
raise and moment.
Indeed.
And I just sort of good time to say
thank you to everybody that has engaged
so far and to all of you who will engage
in the future and there's a big exciting
journey ahead of us. I know we say this
all the time and maybe it sort of sounds
cliche, but we really think that this is
a group effort and this is a community
effort and really excited to bring a
platform to you and then excited to see
what you build on top of it.
Thanks everyone.
Amazing. Cheers.
Thanks and tune in to the next episode
when Guy will be back as the host.
Next week.
Yeah, indeed. Like it or not.
Thanks for tuning in. Join us next time
on the AI Native Dev, brought to you by
Tesseract.